(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Good evening
and welcome to Top Gear
where, tonight,
we're talking about
unusual specimens,
where, tonight,
we're talking about
unusual specimens,
where, tonight,
we're talking about
unusual specimens,
not Ant and Wreck over there,
but rare cars.
Because if you want to get
your hands on a truly rare car,
you could spend millions
on a machine like this,
one of 14 right-hand drive
Ferrari 275 GTS.
It's just beautiful.
Look at it.
It is nice but you could go
the cheaper route.
If you do a bit of digging,
for not much money,
you can find
some properly rare cars,
the last of their kinds.
Yeah, cars that
were once common
but are now nearly extinct.
Yeah, cars that
were once common
but are now nearly extinct.
Yeah, cars that
were once common
but are now nearly extinct.
So, the producers told Fred
and me to go out
and pick the rarest,
cheapest cars we could find
and then meet up with them
in Borneo.
PADDY: Borneo.
A vast jungle island
over three times the size
of Great Britain,
a unique ecosystem
that's home to some of
the strangest,
rarest beasts on Earth
that's home to some of
the strangest,
rarest beasts on Earth
and about to be home
to two more.
- FREDDIE: Come on.
- (PADDY GROANS)
Come on.
- Ah.
- Come on!
How are you?
Good to see you.
- From Bolton.
- Right...
Oh, cars.
FREDDIE: I can't wait to see
what you brought.
Now, let me tell you,
I've been to some
very mysterious parts
of the internet
- finding this car.
- I'm sure you have, Paddy.
- This is a proper, rare one-off.
- Right.
I give you
the Matra Bagheera S.
Feast your eyes on that, son.
Mid-engine, rear-wheel drive,
low centre of gravity,
proper sports car, Fred.
FREDDIE: Push-button, nice.
PADDY: Three seats.
Did somebody say McLaren F1?
- FREDDIE: No.
- Yes, I did.
There's only four in the UK.
This is the only
right-hand drive that
Matra did theirselves.
This is the only
right-hand drive that
Matra did theirselves.
And, just for extra points,
this is the original brochure
for this car.
And that car you're looking
at there, the original, is that.
- Seriously? That is the same?
- That is that, my friend.
Bagheera.
So, it's named after
a Disney character?
- I'll forgive your ignorance.
- How much?
Six grand, just under.
Six grand.
I'll give you it, it's obscure.
Well, that's the point, Fred.
That's the point.
- Is it quick?
- Quick?
Oh! 118 top end.
Look at how low this car is.
Look at the ground clearance.
Well, yeah, it's low
because it's a sports car, Fred.
But you're in Borneo.
Have you seen the terrain
you're going to be going on?
- This is useless.
- I've never been
to Borneo before!
- This is useless.
- I've never been
to Borneo before!
I'm not well-travelled
like you.
Come here,
let me show you this.
This is what
you should have had.
This is the car
that is going to
wipe the floor with you.
This is the car
that is going to
wipe the floor with you.
I present to you
the Austin Allegro estate.
Both British and exotic.
Well, listen,
I don't want to disappoint you,
but the words "British"
and "exotic"
don't go together.
but the words "British"
and "exotic"
don't go together.
- Paddy...
- It's an Allegro.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
- I mean, there's loads of them.
- No, no, not this Allegro.
This is an estate.
This is rarer, Paddy. Rarer.
Just a couple knocking about.
And it's three and a half gra.
Half the price of that,
more or less.
Yeah, I know it's half the price
'cause it's half the car.
Half the price, double the car.
There's no way
that's getting across Borneo.
This is mint.
This is as fast as the day
it left the factory.
- So, very slow, then.
- Faster than yours.
Fa...
PADDY: Well, we'd soon see.
FREDDIE: Three,
two, one,
go.
Come on, Matra, let's go.
Oh, bloomin' heck.
I've got the cover on the back.
It's acting like a parachute
as well. That's not happening.
PADDY: French engineering
at its best!
Suppose he's got a bit of drag.
That's what he'll be saying.
"I've got a bit of drag
with this at the back of my car.
"The dust sheet's
slowing me down."
Ugh. Look at Paddy.
He'll be all happy
with himself.
Ugh. Look at Paddy.
He'll be all happy
with himself.
Well done, Paddy,
you've won in a sports car.
PADDY: Now, the mission we've
been given for our classics
was a simple one,
PADDY: Now, the mission we've
been given for our classics
was a simple one,
PADDY: Now, the mission we've
been given for our classics
was a simple one,
PADDY: Now, the mission we've
been given for our classics
was a simple one,
head up the road out of town
and keep driving
until we could drive no more.
But, just because
the route was simple,
it didn't mean
it would be easy.
God. I've literally only just
got off the airstrip
and we're struggling here.
If I was to draw a car I didn't
want to drive around Borneo,
I reckon I'd draw that.
PADDY: But survive the journey
and we've been told
our rare beasts might just
earn themselves a place
and we've been told
our rare beasts might just
earn themselves a place
and we've been told
our rare beasts might just
earn themselves a place
in one of the world's
most legendary car collections,
a place that, frankly,
my car was made for.
Matra Bagheera.
Wow.
I love the steering wheel.
I like the little flat bit
at the bottom,
very Lamborghini-esque.
I like the little flat bit
at the bottom,
very Lamborghini-esque.
In fact, at its launch,
it was known as
the little Lamborghini,
and I can see why.
Matra is almost
forgotten nowadays,
but, 40 years ago,
it led the world in motorsport.
In 1969, Matra won
the F1 World Championships
with Jackie Stewart.
And it won Le Mans three times,
1972, 1973, and 1974.
Proper pedigree, this car.
Phew!
I'm having some of
my cooling spray.
Oh.
Bit down here.
Oh, God, a pothole!
Ooh, flipping heck!
FREDDIE: Paddy's rushing.
This is the tortoise
and the hare, this.
You've brought a sports car
to Borneo.
Go on, you rush around
scratching the bottom,
I'm just going to take it
nice and easy in my Allegro.
Now, this is the HL line
which means it's the posh one.
You get the head rests.
You get a massive quartz clock.
So you can keep
your Bentley Mulsannes
and your Rolls-Royce Phantoms,
this is pure luxury.
PADDY: After a couple of hours
on the road,
our progress was good.
But, heading into the hills,
and still tiptoeing
around potholes,
Borneo threw in a new,
unavoidable obstacle,
mud.
PADDY: Come on, Bagheera.
Oh, God.
Oh, this is tricky.
Oh, my word.
PADDY: We're going in.
FREDDIE: Nice and slow, Pad.
I'm giving it some!
How are you going to get
the nose up that hill?
PADDY: Go on, Bagheera.
Go on!
Yes! Yes!
Yes! (LAUGHS)
Whoa!
Up we go!
That is unbelievable!
Whoo!
What a car!
Go on.
Oh. Hang on.
I might have pushed
the girl too far.
Let's try this.
(ENGINE REVVING)
Oh, Paddy's stopped.
FREDDIE: You right, Pads?
Wha...
Slight technical.
(FLY BUZZING)
What the frigging hell's
that in my car?
Get out!
Oh, yes.
Can't believe I've just been
overtaken by an Allegro.
Fred, I might need
a bit of help here.
I might have to get out
and give it a little bit of
a shunt.
I might have to get out
and give it a little bit of
a shunt.
I might have to get out
and give it a little bit of
a shunt.
I tell you what we need,
we need some rocks or something,
don't we, under the wheels?
I'll fish some out.
You sort them out,
I'll get some out of here.
You've got to be careful
in here, though, Paddy.
Any chance of something with
a bit of substantiality to it?
Well, do you want
to have a look?
There's all sorts in here.
He brought that out.
What's that going to do?
In here, Paddy, in here
there's tarantulas, right?
- Flying snakes.
- They're not
going to bother you.
- Flying snakes.
- They're not
going to bother you.
Sumatran cobras
that spray poison
in your eyes and blind you.
Sumatran cobras
that spray poison
in your eyes and blind you.
- You'll be all right.
- Black leopards,
stalk you in silence,
- You'll be all right.
- Black leopards,
stalk you in silence,
- You'll be all right.
- Black leopards,
stalk you in silence,
one bite on the throat,
you're dead.
You're from Preston,
there's worse round there.
FREDDIE: Back, back!
(WHIRRING)
Get a brick under
the other side as well, Fred.
Oh, you sit there,
you're all right,
I'll get the bricks.
- Well, I'm the pilot, aren't I?
- FREDDIE: Bloomin' heck.
PADDY: There's them who sit
in the car and reverse
and there's them who put rocks
under the tyres, son.
(ENGINE REVS)
FREDDIE: Go on.
What about giving it
a bit of a...
at the front,
give it a push at the front.
How about you get out
for two minutes?
Lift it!
Oh, that's it, go on, Fred!
It's not even a tonne,
this car, it's lightweight.
Oh.
FREDDIE: Stop!
What is it?
It's all right,
you don't need it.
- Oh, God.
- You're all right.
- Oh, I can't believe
that's happened.
- It's all right.
- Oh, I can't believe
that's happened.
- It's all right.
40 years, not a scratch.
PADDY: It had been
a busy morning for the cars,
so, reaching a nearby village,
we decided to stop for a break.
Don't be intimidated
by me getting my arms out.
FREDDIE: I'm really not.
Like a dinner lady,
look at them.
PADDY: And,
as luck would have it,
we turned up to a highlight
of the local sporting calendar,
Buffalo Race Day.
(SINGING)
FREDDIE:
This is quite a big thing,
isn't it, today?
FREDDIE:
This is quite a big thing,
isn't it, today?
Get some food here, eh?
Oh, they're off.
Pick one, Paddy, pick one.
- PADDY: They're off.
- Go on.
- Number one.
- PADDY: Number four, me.
- Number four.
- Yeah, the one at the front.
PADDY: Come on, number four!
- FREDDIE: Go on, lad!
- Come on, number four!
Go on, number one!
Go on, one!
- He's got him.
- Oh, no!
- Oh!
- Four.
That was four.
Four by a nose.
- Good job I've got these on.
- Oh!
- Have you not got them?
- No, I haven't.
You know, you just make them
into shorts.
Get a bit of air to your legs,
you see, Fred.
PADDY: And, by the time
the second race was over,
Freddie had found
the on-site catering.
Ooh, exotic.
Got a bit of fruit.
Durian fruit.
- Chatting to the fella...
- Pfft!
- You all right?
- Please stop
putting it under my nose.
- You all right?
- Please stop
putting it under my nose.
- It's very prickly.
- Whoa! What you doing?
The texture's like...
Do you know when you get
a cheese slice melted?
The texture's like...
Do you know when you get
a cheese slice melted?
- Yeah.
- That's the texture of it.
Whoa, man, that smells.
- Go on.
- What do you mean "go on"?
- Hang on.
- You said you were hungry.
Wait a minute.
Yeah, I wanted a...
It's all right.
- You're struggling.
- Tell you what...
- You're struggling!
- I tell you what...
- (PADDY LAUGHS)
- No, it's fine, Paddy.
You went...
Oh.
- It was just a surprise.
- No, I'm all right.
- Come on!
- No.
Just tasted some.
- Take them away.
- No...
Say no offence when you
go over, just say...
tell them I'm a vegan.
Say no offence when you
go over, just say...
tell them I'm a vegan.
Say no offence when you
go over, just say...
tell them I'm a vegan.
Yep.
There you are.
Pass it down.
- Thank you.
- You're welcome.
- Got these sago grubs.
- What the f... What's that?
Sago grubs,
they're a delicacy.
- They're alive, man.
- You said you wanted protein.
Oh, no, I can't...
I mean, look at them,
they're quite cute.
Oh, no, I can't...
I mean, look at them,
they're quite cute.
- If I have one,
will you have one?
- We're not eight.
- If I have one,
will you have one?
- We're not eight.
- But we're in it together,
aren't we?
- We are not eight.
- But we're in it together,
aren't we?
- We are not eight.
Put your hand there and I'll
put my hand there and all that.
What are you doing?
- You need
to live a little, Paddy.
- What are you doing? I can't...
- You need
to live a little, Paddy.
- What are you doing? I can't...
I tell you what,
it's a funny feeling, that.
Oh, look at that.
Go on.
PADDY: Fuelled up
on his high protein... grub,
next, Flintoff fancied
his chances out on the track.
(CROWD CHEERING)
What the hell is he doing?
Over here. Come on.
Paddy, lad, I'm in the lead!
Go on! I'm winning.
Oh! Oh! Oh, no. Come on.
PADDY: But, before
Freddie Dettori could
do himself or a buffalo
PADDY: But, before
Freddie Dettori could
do himself or a buffalo
a career-ending injury,
I thought it best
we get back on the move.
And, once again,
picking our way
along the only road north,
And, once again,
picking our way
along the only road north,
And, once again,
picking our way
along the only road north,
the afternoon played out,
well, pretty much
as the morning had.
Come on.
Right, wait there,
I'm going to give you a push.
Hang on, I might have that.
Try that.
- (ENGINE REVS)
- (BLEEPING)
Paddy, wait!
I'll tell you when!
PADDY: Oh, come on.
Come on, Bagheera.
Oh-ho!
First gear's gone in! Yes!
That's the first time to...
What in the name of God is th?
Where did that come from? Oh!
Oh, my God, that's savage.
Flippin' heck!
I can't even get it into a gear.
Pump, pump, pump.
Bloody thing's cut out on me.
Oh, no.
I've no engine.
Oh! Oh!
Oh, God. Argh!
Oh, there's bloody flies
coming in at me. Oh!
Argh!
Oh!
(PANTING)
Either this has got
heated seats
or I've just had an accident.
Look at this.
No pride in his car whatsoever.
Look at that. He doesn't care,
McGuinness, he doesn't care.
When did that come off?
Down that hill.
I stopped to pick it up.
- (HORN BEEPS)
- PADDY: Oh, look at this.
We're holding up the road here.
It's all right,
they'll see that
and they'll go,
"Oh, bit of class.
"He's a Matra driver."
"Look at that knobhead
driving that French car."
- PADDY: Need a push up, boys.
- Do you reckon you can push...
You fancy helping us
push this, please?
PADDY: Need a push,
need a push.
- FREDDIE: Who's the lightest,
smallest?
- MAN: The small one.
- FREDDIE: Who's the lightest,
smallest?
- MAN: The small one.
- FREDDIE: Who's the lightest,
smallest?
- MAN: The small one.
- The small one. Get yourself in.
- FREDDIE: This lad here.
PADDY: You steer, we'll push.
That's it.
Just before we go, it's the oy
right-hand drive Bagheera, th,
- made by Matra.
- FREDDIE: Are we ready?
- Right, lads, come on.
- PADDY: That's it.
- Push!
- Oh, we're on it,
we're on it!
- Push!
- Oh, we're on it,
we're on it!
FREDDIE:
Come on, lads, come on.
Let's go, come on!
FREDDIE:
Come on, lads, come on.
Let's go, come on!
PADDY:
Yes, lads, come on, push!
(ALL LAUGHING)
FREDDIE: Oh-whey-oh!
Oh-oh-oh!
FREDDIE: And, just to be clear,
while Paddy was busy
deconstructing his Bagheera...
Oh!
Ooh!
Oh, no, there goes
my rear view mirror.
That's gone.
Oh, no, there goes
my rear view mirror.
That's gone.
FREDDIE: ... the Allegro 1.5 HL
hadn't missed a beat.
Here we go.
I've had 4x4s
that can't do this.
BMW X5, I couldn't get it
off the drive when it snowed.
Me drive was only like that.
Look at this!
I tell you what,
the people at British Leyland,
they had a bad reputation
for going home early.
Not the bloke
who put this one together.
He stayed on a Friday.
He thought, "One day,
my car is going to be driven
"by a fat, ex-cricketer
with ginger hair
through Borneo."
"by a fat, ex-cricketer
with ginger hair
through Borneo."
PADDY:
As the day wore on
eventually
the light began to fade.
Oh, God.
Poor visibility, head lamps
from the '70s, and it's raining.
Bloomin' heck.
PADDY: Oh, no, what's happened
to my wipers?
I've lost a wiper.
FREDDIE: But we'd been told
to drive until we could
drive no more,
FREDDIE: But we'd been told
to drive until we could
drive no more,
FREDDIE: But we'd been told
to drive until we could
drive no more,
so, that's exactly
what we did.
FREDDIE:
How are you feeling,
big lad?
FREDDIE:
How are you feeling,
big lad?
Oh, I'm ready
for my pit, son.
FREDDIE:
Me and you both.
Whoa, whoa, whoa, whoa.
What is...
What's going on?
Hello.
Okay.
Paddy, I think
these are Gurkhas.
Just be good.
- Sir?
- Yes.
This is for you.
(SIGHS)
- PADDY: Whoo!
- What did he say, Paddy?
What's he after?
- PADDY: Whoo!
- What did he say, Paddy?
What's he after?
Dish it out to me.
"Tomorrow, you will face
the ultimate test.
"With the help of
the army's elite shock
force troop, the Gurkhas,
"With the help of
the army's elite shock
force troop, the Gurkhas,
"With the help of
the army's elite shock
force troop, the Gurkhas,
"you're going off-road,
"really off-road."
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
CHRIS:
What was that? What's that?
Why's he doing that?
CHRIS:
What was that? What's that?
Why's he doing that?
- Don't worry about that.
- It's horrible.
It's horrible. Okay.
- Don't worry about that.
- It's horrible.
It's horrible. Okay.
- Don't worry about that.
- It's horrible.
It's horrible. Okay.
Congratulations, Andrew,
you are definitely moving up
in the world.
Congratulations, Andrew,
you are definitely moving up
in the world.
Congratulations, Andrew,
you are definitely moving up
in the world.
You've gone from
pedalo to buffalo.
- Firstly, it's Fred till
I tell you otherwise.
- Okay, sorry.
- Firstly, it's Fred till
I tell you otherwise.
- Okay, sorry.
And the other thing,
buffaloes are easier to stay on
than a pedalo.
And the other thing,
buffaloes are easier to stay on
than a pedalo.
And the other thing,
buffaloes are easier to stay on
than a pedalo.
- It does help
being sober as well.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
- It does help
being sober as well.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
I'm not going to lie.
We'll get back to that film
and the Gurkhas a little later,
and, let me tell you,
those lads do not mess about.
Now, while these two were off
flouncing around in the jungle,
I was busy doing
some real world
consumer journalism,
I was busy doing
some real world
consumer journalism,
I was busy doing
some real world
consumer journalism,
a very thorough review
of the new Rolls-Royce.
CHRIS:
It's called the Cullinan.
It costs a quarter of
a million pounds.
And, though it might
look like an SUV,
according to Rolls,
it isn't an SUV.
No, this is an all-terrain,
high-bodied car.
So, an SUV, then.
And to all those people saying,
"Should Rolls-Royce really build
"a massive SUV?"
I say, well, why not?
If anyone's entitled to build
a massive, off-road tank,
it's them.
If anyone's entitled to build
a massive, off-road tank,
it's them.
If anyone's entitled to build
a massive, off-road tank,
it's them.
If anyone's entitled to build
a massive, off-road tank,
it's them.
It's hardly like
their normal cars
are small and dainty, is it?
It's hardly like
their normal cars
are small and dainty, is it?
Furthermore, 100 years ago,
Rolls' entire
best-car-in-the-world image
was based on a building
off-road vehicles
because there were no roads.
Just ask Lawrence of Arabia.
And the Cullinan
is a proper off-roader.
It's got four-wheel-drive,
it'll wade through
half a metre of water,
it'll realistically go
anywhere you'd expect
your £250,000 off-roader to go.
But, let's face it,
the Cullinan owner
isn't going to do any of that.
They're going
to drive around on-road,
from this very high
driving position,
wondering why everyone else
looks a bit poor.
And, out on the road,
the Cullinan is every bit
as refined and imperious
as you'd expect
the Cullinan is every bit
as refined and imperious
as you'd expect
the Cullinan is every bit
as refined and imperious
as you'd expect
from the world's
most expensive SUV.
Listen to that.
The silence is just glorious.
This is the most refined
SUV ever made.
You really don't even know
the engine's switched on.
I mean,
driving on this road now,
there's no suspension noise,
no tyre noise.
And the ride,
it's just extraordinary.
It is so supple,
it's like the road ahead
of you's just been resurfaced
with marshmallows.
And, like every other
luxury SUV out there,
the Cullinan
doesn't just do comfort...
it also does power.
And it really is
more than powerful enough.
It has a twin-turbo-charged
6.75 litre V12,
560hp.
I'm not sure anyone
is going to be brave enough
to really hustle one of these,
though.
It goes really,
really quickly.
And it does a great job
of hiding all of its weight
until you get to a corner
like that...
(TYRES SCREECH)
and you are very aware
of how heavy it is.
Let's be honest,
this isn't an SUV
for driving hard,
Let's be honest,
this isn't an SUV
for driving hard,
Let's be honest,
this isn't an SUV
for driving hard,
it's an SUV
for wafting along in
glorious, soothing silence.
it's an SUV
for wafting along in
glorious, soothing silence.
it's an SUV
for wafting along in
glorious, soothing silence.
it's an SUV
for wafting along in
glorious, soothing silence.
And, for that,
the Cullinan is in
a class of its own.
And, for that,
the Cullinan is in
a class of its own.
And, for that,
the Cullinan is in
a class of its own.
However, it does have
one, teeny-tiny problem.
It is, to use
a technical, automotive term,
utterly hideous to look at.
I mean, it's a little bit
new London taxi there,
it's a little bit
Chinese knock-off,
it's all bad.
I mean, look at the grille.
All that money,
that design team,
that's the best
they can come up with?
It just looks like
they've taken
any old boxy SUV
It just looks like
they've taken
any old boxy SUV
and just slapped a grille on it
and a flying lady.
She must be gutted.
And I know looks are
a subjective thing,
but this is just wrong.
In fact, I'm going
to get inside 'cause
it's safer on my eyes.
In fact, I'm going
to get inside 'cause
it's safer on my eyes.
Argh!
It really is
quite an achievement.
Rolls has somehow managed
to build a £250,000 car
that turns heads
for all the wrong reasons.
♪♪ Hallelujah... ♪♪
Sorry. Sorry.
♪♪ Hallelujah, hallelujah... ♪
It's not my car.
♪♪ Hallelujah
♪♪ Hallelujah, hallelujah
♪♪ Hallelujah ♪♪
CHRIS: But there's something
much worse going on here.
The Cullinan should feel like
the peak of British engineering
but, actually,
it just feels cynical.
It doesn't feel like
it was created through passion,
or love, or innovation,
It doesn't feel like
it was created through passion,
or love, or innovation,
It doesn't feel like
it was created through passion,
or love, or innovation,
It doesn't feel like
it was created through passion,
or love, or innovation,
it just feels like
it was created to make money.
Raw greed.
Because, let's face it,
there are too many
rich people on this planet
for this tasteless car
not to exist.
I'm an apologist
for the motor car,
fast, big, inefficient,
I'll defend them
'cause I love cars,
fast, big, inefficient,
I'll defend them
'cause I love cars,
fast, big, inefficient,
I'll defend them
'cause I love cars,
I'm passionate about them.
But I cannot construct
a defence for this car.
I'm in the flag-bearer
for British engineering,
a Rolls-Royce,
and I'm ashamed to be in it.
So, if you want to experience
a world-class piece
of British engineering
that doesn't make
you loath yourself,
you don't want one of these.
Oh, no.
You want one of these.
Now, that is
British engineering.
Watch this.
Now, that is
British engineering.
Watch this.
Now, that is
British engineering.
Watch this.
The Brompton folding bicycle.
What a machine.
Frankly, it's a blessed relief.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
CHRIS: I mean, I'm not...
I'm not being...
I do have to point out
there's no Cullinan.
- There are no flies
on you, Fred.
- Where is it?
- There are no flies
on you, Fred.
- Where is it?
Your powers of observation
are amazing.
Look, we asked Rolls-Royce
if we could borrow one,
they said no,
so we had to rent one.
And they said no
'cause they were worried,
I don't know why,
And they said no
'cause they were worried,
I don't know why,
And they said no
'cause they were worried,
I don't know why,
they thought
we were going to be
rude about it.
they thought
we were going to be
rude about it.
You were rude about it.
Oh, come on, I think
we just pointed out
the obvious, didn't we?
Oh, come on, I think
we just pointed out
the obvious, didn't we?
Look, it deserves
a kicking and they're not
the only ones, either.
Look, it deserves
a kicking and they're not
the only ones, either.
Look, it deserves
a kicking and they're not
the only ones, either.
Everyone's making these big,
large, executive SUVs.
You know,
Aston Martin's at it,
Lamborghini's done it,
You know,
Aston Martin's at it,
Lamborghini's done it,
Bentley's done it,
but there's something
about the Rolls
Bentley's done it,
but there's something
about the Rolls
that makes it more hateful
than all the others.
- It's just hideous to look at.
- It's not that bad.
In comparison to the Bentley
and the Lambo,
I'd have it every day
of the week.
Oh. It's Rolls-Royce, Paddy.
- British at its best.
- Oh, no.
- I'm sorry, are you
having a laugh?
- No.
- I'm sorry, are you
having a laugh?
- No.
- You would drive around
in that car?
- Mate, what's wrong with it?
- You would drive around
in that car?
- Mate, what's wrong with it?
Tell you what, then,
you open the boot,
you get a Brompton out,
Tell you what, then,
you open the boot,
you get a Brompton out,
there's nothing
more pretentious on the road
than a Brompton.
there's nothing
more pretentious on the road
than a Brompton.
- "Look at me
on my foldy-up bike."
- No, I've got to...
- "Look at me
on my foldy-up bike."
- No, I've got to...
- (LAUGHTER)
- Jeez, come on, Chris...
Shall we move on?
Because now it's time
for tonight's studio guest,
Shall we move on?
Because now it's time
for tonight's studio guest,
the fantastic Bob Mortimer.
Here's what happened
when we met him out
on the track earlier today.
Here's what happened
when we met him out
on the track earlier today.
Here's what happened
when we met him out
on the track earlier today.
- Behave, you two.
- You can have some as well.
(APPLAUSE)
Hello, Bob. Hiya, Paddy.
Hiya, Freddie. Hiya, Chris.
- How are you, boss?
- Thanks for having us.
Welcome to the Top Gear
Width Restrictor challenge,
okay?
Welcome to the Top Gear
Width Restrictor challenge,
okay?
Welcome to the Top Gear
Width Restrictor challenge,
okay?
- Right. Yeah.
- Very, very simple.
- You've got to take this car...
- Yeah.
and you've got
to drive through there
as fast as you can,
and you've got
to drive through there
as fast as you can,
and you have to nominate
someone to compete against.
Might I suggest you choose
the person you think
might be the slowest.
- Paddy.
- Oh! (FREDDIE LAUGHS)
Ooh. Oh,
he's not happy with that.
Here we go.
Great car, this.
Come on.
Here we go.
Great car, this.
Come on.
Here we go.
Great car, this.
Come on.
Sport mode,
Bob won't think of that.
This is how competitive
Paddy is,
he started way back
so he can get some speed up.
She's an old girl.
Come on. 70.
CHRIS: He suits the Jag.
I can imagine him
in one of those
lurking around wine bars.
I can imagine him
in one of those
lurking around wine bars.
- Yeah.
- Sort of Watford area.
100, we're at 100.
We're at 100. We're at 100.
Oh! He's through, Bob.
Ooh, that were tight!
(TYRES SCREECH)
Well, I was very impressed.
She'll go, the old girl.
That was impressive. Go on.
- PADDY: 101!
- CHRIS: Race you back.
- Beat that, Sir Bob.
- I won't. Beat that.
- Now, did you touch anything?
- Well, little nick
on the wing mirror.
- Now, did you touch anything?
- Well, little nick
on the wing mirror.
- Now, did you touch anything?
- Well, little nick
on the wing mirror.
- Oh, hello.
- Oh, oh. No, no. Whoa.
It's intact, look.
- CHRIS: Is the glass smashed?
- No.
- There you go.
- Get off that.
So I think that does count.
101mph is your speed
to beat, Bob.
Well, I won't be beating that.
- Do you want me to try
and do 100mph?
- I want you to beat Paddy.
- Do you want me to try
and do 100mph?
- I want you to beat Paddy.
- (BOB LAUGHS)
- I really want you
to beat Paddy.
Three, two, one, go.
Come on, Bob.
Don't lift off.
They're barely moving.
I can't even pick... Oh, 36.
- I am a sinner!
- 70! Come on, go, Bob!
Go! I'm nervous.
I don't usually get (BLEEP)
No, Bob, no.
No!
Oh! You got through, Bob!
(BOTH LAUGHING)
Did you have the handbrake on,
Bob, or what?
In Bob's mind,
we were supersonic.
- It was...
- Bob, we didn't need
the speed camera.
- It was...
- Bob, we didn't need
the speed camera.
Oh, I know, but I've
enjoyed myself so much.
- Honest.
- (BOTH LAUGHING)
It's not all about speed,
is it?
That's the first time
I've been frightened
in a long time.
That's the first time
I've been frightened
in a long time.
First of all,
can I announce your speed?
- What do you think you did?
- Oh, I think I...
I really want it
to be 60 but...
- Yes!
- Oh, it is?
- Oh! Oh, that's all right!
- That's all right! Get in!
- That's all right!
- And one point of conjecture,
- you went through at 60,
you didn't touch anything.
- No.
- you went through at 60,
you didn't touch anything.
- No.
- you went through at 60,
you didn't touch anything.
- No.
He may have done 101
but he whacked a wing mirror,
so I'm not sure that
you haven't scored
a moral victory here.
so I'm not sure that
you haven't scored
a moral victory here.
- He's chuffed with himself,
isn't he?
- Oh, all the time.
- He's chuffed with himself,
isn't he?
- Oh, all the time.
For no apparent reason.
Just shows that sometimes
the tortoise beats the hare,
doesn't it?
Just shows that sometimes
the tortoise beats the hare,
doesn't it?
BOB: Yeah. Sometimes the bull
beats the kestrel.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
- Do you know what I mean?
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Please welcome comedy legend
Bob Mortimer!
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Hi, Paddy. Hi, Chris.
Hiya, Freddie.
- Oh!
Whoa!
Thanks for having us.
- PADDY: That was tight.
- That was tight, yeah.
You went fast at first
and then you took
your foot off the gas, why?
You went fast at first
and then you took
your foot off the gas, why?
You went fast at first
and then you took
your foot off the gas, why?
'Cause I got frightened.
- Right, okay.
- You got frightened?
- I was bricking it
in that passenger seat.
- Yes.
- I was bricking it
in that passenger seat.
- Yes.
- I was bricking it
in that passenger seat.
- Yes.
- I kind of smelt that, yes.
- (ALL LAUGHING)
- Kind of.
- Apologies.
- But let's start
at the beginning.
- Yeah.
- But let's start
at the beginning.
- Yeah.
What was your first car?
My first car was a Lexus LS400.
PADDY: Big.
That's a very big,
not-normal, first car.
- When did you pass
your driving test?
- Not till my late 30s.
- When did you pass
your driving test?
- Not till my late 30s.
- When did you pass
your driving test?
- Not till my late 30s.
You know, when, my wife
was having a baby,
so you think, you know,
you might have to drive
to the hospital.
so you think, you know,
you might have to drive
to the hospital.
so you think, you know,
you might have to drive
to the hospital.
- Drive to the hospital...
- It helps.
Yeah, with some towels
and some hot water
on the back-seat, so I thought
I'd have to learn, so, yeah.
I didn't know this.
This is amazing, everybody.
Bob used to be
the voice of Churchill the dog
from the adverts.
Bob used to be
the voice of Churchill the dog
from the adverts.
Bob used to be
the voice of Churchill the dog
from the adverts.
- I can't believe it!
- (CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
- Oh, yes.
- (CHEERING)
Yes! Yes!
- (LAUGHTER)
- Yes!
Yeah, we went into a voice booth
and they had this character,
a dog, and said,
"Can you come up
with a voice for it?"
a dog, and said,
"Can you come up
with a voice for it?"
a dog, and said,
"Can you come up
with a voice for it?"
And I also, do you remember
Deryck Guyler?
"Oh, what you doing?"
And I also, do you remember
Deryck Guyler?
"Oh, what you doing?"
And I also, do you remember
Deryck Guyler?
"Oh, what you doing?"
- Yeah.
- I did it like that
and that became kind of what
I'm best known for,
although I'm not known
for it as it were.
- How long did you
do it for, those adverts?
- I did it for a long time.
- How long did you
do it for, those adverts?
- I did it for a long time.
For, I'm thinking, like,
ten years or something.
Did they just keep
getting you back in
or did you just use it,
Did they just keep
getting you back in
or did you just use it,
because it's just the same,
"Oh, yes," it's just that
on every advert.
because it's just the same,
"Oh, yes," it's just that
on every advert.
because it's just the same,
"Oh, yes," it's just that
on every advert.
Every time I'd have to go in
and do an, "Oh, yes.
"Oh, yes! Oh, yes."
You know,
with those instructions.
"Say this one like you're sad."
"Oh, yes."
(ALL LAUGHING)
But, yeah, I'd have to,
so they must have thousands
upon thousands of,
But, yeah, I'd have to,
so they must have thousands
upon thousands of,
But, yeah, I'd have to,
so they must have thousands
upon thousands of,
- "Oh, yes," somewhere.
- PADDY: Brilliant.
Shall we talk about
your new show,
Gone Fishing
with Paul Whitehouse.
- Oh, thank you, yeah.
- Now, I'm not
massively into fishing.
- Oh, thank you, yeah.
- Now, I'm not
massively into fishing.
I mean, I've done a little bit,
but I love the show.
- Why do you think it's been
so successful?
- Do you know what?
- Why do you think it's been
so successful?
- Do you know what?
I think it's a little bit of
what Last Of
The Summer Wine used to have.
I think it's a little bit of
what Last Of
The Summer Wine used to have.
I think it's a little bit of
what Last Of
The Summer Wine used to have.
It's older fellas,
it's very gentle.
It comes across on camera
that you genuinely love it,
though.
It comes across on camera
that you genuinely love it,
though.
It comes across on camera
that you genuinely love it,
though.
I absolutely adore it.
It's, like,
not the fishing as such.
I adore at my age
just being away.
- It's like being 15 again
with your best mate.
- Yeah.
- It's like being 15 again
with your best mate.
- Yeah.
- Messing around
on a river bank.
- Yeah.
- Messing around
on a river bank.
- Yeah.
- Going to the boozer afterwards.
Having a pie, 'cause
the wife's not there,
so she won't stop me
eating pies.
Oh, have you been put on a stop
with pies, have you?
Yeah, 'cause of me heart stuff,
I'm not allowed to eat
anything nice.
Yeah, 'cause of me heart stuff,
I'm not allowed to eat
anything nice.
(LAUGHTER)
The second series
is on later on
this summer as well.
The second series
is on later on
this summer as well.
- Summer, yeah.
- I think we've got a clip,
actually. Let's have a look.
- Summer, yeah.
- I think we've got a clip,
actually. Let's have a look.
- Bob. Oh, have
a drink from that.
- (PAUL CHUCKLES)
- Bob. Oh, have
a drink from that.
- (PAUL CHUCKLES)
- Bob. Oh, have
a drink from that.
- (PAUL CHUCKLES)
- Isn't it glorious?
- That's fantastic.
It's a par four this, Paul,
which means it should
take four minutes.
It's a par four this, Paul,
which means it should
take four minutes.
It's a par four this, Paul,
which means it should
take four minutes.
(BOB LAUGHS)
I'm sorry,
I shouldn't laugh, Paul.
I shouldn't laugh.
And nor should you,
you should be ashamed.
(BOB SNIGGERS)
- Whoa!
- Straight in the rough!
Well, I'm not using
what you used.
What did you use?
Look at the size of this!
I bet he's played it before.
- No-one's been...
- (PAUL LAUGHS)
Come on, hapless Bob.
- Whoa!
- Whoa! Look at it go!
Where did it go?
- Nobody knows.
- No!
(LAUGHTER AND APPLAUSE)
Bob, Bob, you're golfing there,
obviously, you fish.
Historically, you're doing
boring things but making them
look really fun.
Historically, you're doing
boring things but making them
look really fun.
Historically, you're doing
boring things but making them
look really fun.
- Do you fancy having
a crack at cricket?
- (LAUGHTER)
- Do you fancy having
a crack at cricket?
- (LAUGHTER)
- Do you fancy having
a crack at cricket?
- (LAUGHTER)
Anyway, it's time
to see your lap.
- Thank you.
- How did you find the GT86?
Well, when I went round with
Stig, I found it terrifying,
but, actually, when
I was at the controls,
not so much.
but, actually, when
I was at the controls,
not so much.
but, actually, when
I was at the controls,
not so much.
Not really.
It's interesting, Stig.
- You're trying to work out
what or who he is, you know?
- Yeah.
- You're trying to work out
what or who he is, you know?
- Yeah.
- You're trying to work out
what or who he is, you know?
- Yeah.
He's got very thin thighs,
have you noticed?
He's really thin. Made me think,
"Maybe he's part thrush?"
(LAUGHTER)
- Anyway, who'd like
to see Bob's lap?
- PADDY: Yes! Come on.
- Anyway, who'd like
to see Bob's lap?
- PADDY: Yes! Come on.
AUDIENCE: Yeah!
All right.
Let's take a look.
CHRIS: Off the line.
I'm not going to say much here,
'cause Bob's ace.
CHRIS: Off the line.
I'm not going to say much here,
'cause Bob's ace.
CHRIS: Off the line.
I'm not going to say much here,
'cause Bob's ace.
IN GEORDIE ACCENT:
Howie, Mickey,
let's go down the retail park
and do some doughnuts.
And then have some chicken
and throw the bones at Halfords.
CHRIS: Were you just
in your own little
world at this point?
CHRIS: Were you just
in your own little
world at this point?
To be honest with you, yeah.
- I mean, it doesn't look quick.
- BOB:
No, it's not quick, I'm sure.
- I mean, it doesn't look quick.
- BOB:
No, it's not quick, I'm sure.
- I mean, it doesn't look quick.
- BOB:
No, it's not quick, I'm sure.
It's doing
these sorts of speeds...
that mean that you miss
the price reductions
on the pasties and the pies.
Pasty gone! Pie gone!
Too fast, boy!
CHRIS: He's coming in
to Hammerhead now.
It doesn't look quick
but it's controlled.
He was a late entrant
to the competition.
Nobody knows who he is or where
he's come from but he's fast.
He's fast, all right.
CHRIS: You're speaking
about yourself
in the third person,
CHRIS: You're speaking
about yourself
in the third person,
that's the first sign
of madness, isn't it?
Don't brake, Bob. Don't...
Don't even think about it!
Go, go, go, go, go!
Don't brake!
Don't brake. Brake face!
Oh, he's (BLEEP) his pants,
but that's okay!
Oh, and home. Thank God.
CHRIS:
I don't care how fast that was,
it's the best lap
I've ever watched.
Oh, thank you.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
- You can see
the lap board, Bob.
- Yeah.
- You can see
the lap board, Bob.
- Yeah.
Where would you like to be?
Well, it was very sedate.
I would... I would be so chuffed
if I was above Dara
- (VOCALIZING) O Briain.
- (LAUGHTER)
So, you're setting your sights
quite high there, Bob.
- I've got the result.
- Oh, dear.
And I can tell you,
Bob Mortimer...
you went round our track
in one minute...
- 40...
- Ooh, hey-yup!
eight point four.
So, Bob...
- You're in!
- Hey!
FREDDIE: ... you're just under
Frankie Dettori.
- You've got to be pleased.
- I'm very pleased.
(LAUGHS)
Who'd have thought.
- Ladies and gentlemen,
Bob Mortimer!
- Thank you.
- Ladies and gentlemen,
Bob Mortimer!
- Thank you.
- Ladies and gentlemen,
Bob Mortimer!
- Thank you.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Now, time to get back to Borneo
where, as you'll remember,
the producers had arranged
for the British Army's Gurkha
regiment to interrupt
our journey.
That's because the point
of this film had always been
to work with the Gurkhas
and have a massive off-road
adventure in the jungle,
to work with the Gurkhas
and have a massive off-road
adventure in the jungle,
to work with the Gurkhas
and have a massive off-road
adventure in the jungle,
but the jungle
the Army sends the Gurkhas
to train in is in Brunei,
but the jungle
the Army sends the Gurkhas
to train in is in Brunei,
but the jungle
the Army sends the Gurkhas
to train in is in Brunei,
and the mystery car collector
we were on our way to see
was none other
than the Sultan of Brunei who,
it's fair to say,
wasn't expecting us.
Now, after we landed
back in the UK,
having made this film,
Now, after we landed
back in the UK,
having made this film,
Now, after we landed
back in the UK,
having made this film,
the Sultan announced new laws
making homosexuality
and adultery punishable
by death.
As you can imagine,
we were horrified.
We'd obviously
never have visited Brunei
had that been the case
beforehand.
And, though there's a temporary
halt on enforcing this law,
we thought long and hard
about showing this film.
But the Gurkhas were brilliant,
as were the men and women
of Brunei
But the Gurkhas were brilliant,
as were the men and women
of Brunei
But the Gurkhas were brilliant,
as were the men and women
of Brunei
who helped make
this journey possible,
so part two is for them.
FREDDIE: Morning in Brunei.
Overnight, our rare cars
had been taken off us
and dropped deep
into the jungle.
Now, to prove them worthy
of the Sultan's collection
once and for all,
Now, to prove them worthy
of the Sultan's collection
once and for all,
Now, to prove them worthy
of the Sultan's collection
once and for all,
we'd each been assigned
a three-man squad
of Gurkhas
we'd each been assigned
a three-man squad
of Gurkhas
we'd each been assigned
a three-man squad
of Gurkhas
to help us find them,
bring them out alive
and deliver them
to his palace.
bring them out alive
and deliver them
to his palace.
The heat's baking.
We're travelling down the river
to God knows where.
Safe to say
I'm out of me comfort zone.
I know for a fact,
that in this water,
it's full of crocodiles.
I know for a fact,
that in this water,
it's full of crocodiles.
I'm hanging on.
Is this it? Is this it?
I think we're here.
We're turning round,
we're going somewhere.
What's going on?
We're getting off. Hang on.
We're going.
- PADDY: What the hell's
going on?
- FREDDIE: Don't know, mate.
- PADDY: What the hell's
going on?
- FREDDIE: Don't know, mate.
FREDDIE: Safely ashore,
before we could begin
the hunt for our cars,
FREDDIE: Safely ashore,
before we could begin
the hunt for our cars,
FREDDIE: Safely ashore,
before we could begin
the hunt for our cars,
our new colleagues
wanted to give us
the lay of the land.
our new colleagues
wanted to give us
the lay of the land.
our new colleagues
wanted to give us
the lay of the land.
our new colleagues
wanted to give us
the lay of the land.
- PADDY: Did you see this sign?
- FREDDIE: Yeah.
GURKHA: Wild boar,
that's a pretty big one.
- FREDDIE: Dangerous?
- GURKHA: Very dangerous.
If you see boar in the jungle,
avoid it.
PADDY: What do we do?
Hide behind a tree?
Yeah, run.
- FREDDIE: Run?
- Yeah.
You can see there,
that's from the crocodile,
from the river crocodile.
You can see there,
that's from the crocodile,
from the river crocodile.
You can see there,
that's from the crocodile,
from the river crocodile.
PADDY: Crocodile?
- They're coming out to here?
- Yeah.
Could there be
a nest round here?
- A nest?
- Crocodile nest.
- They put their eggs in.
- GURKHA: Might be.
What else should we look for?
There's boars, crocodiles.
So be aware of
very dry, dry trees.
There could be spiders
and scorpions.
Right.
Basically, nothing is nice.
(PADDY SIGHS)
PADDY: Even with the 2015
Australian I'm A Celebrity
champion for company,
PADDY: Even with the 2015
Australian I'm A Celebrity
champion for company,
PADDY: Even with the 2015
Australian I'm A Celebrity
champion for company,
PADDY: Even with the 2015
Australian I'm A Celebrity
champion for company,
I was well out me depth.
Oh! (BLEEP)
Oh. Oh, eh, eh,
eh, eh, eh, eh.
You all right, Pad?
Have to be careful around here,
hadn't you?
- Oop.
- Oh, look at that.
Is that one of them knives
that can cut through anything
that you see on QVC?
Just told me be careful
with them,
the spikes are poisonous.
Just told me be careful
with them,
the spikes are poisonous.
Just told me be careful
with them,
the spikes are poisonous.
Yeah, it's not something
I were going to go
and exactly try and touch.
How do you think your car's
going to do in here, Paddy?
- Mine?
- FREDDIE: Yeah.
It's called the Bagheera, Fred.
The panther, it were made
for this kind of stuff.
Tell you what, Paddy,
I can't wait to show you
what I've done to my car.
What do you mean,
you've done to your car?
Oh! Argh!
Careful with that.
Oh, God!
Oh! It's a bit brutal,
ain't it?
Where have they
put these cars?
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
- FREDDIE: Oh, my word.
- PADDY: What?
- FREDDIE: Have you ever had
rain like that in your life?
- Oh!
- FREDDIE: Have you ever had
rain like that in your life?
- Oh!
- FREDDIE: Have you ever had
rain like that in your life?
- Oh!
(THUNDER RUMBLES)
It's actually chilly.
- It is cold, ain't it?
- Chilly!
FREDDIE: After two hours
hard trek,
we finally came across
a clearing.
Yes! The cars!
Oh. The cars.
FREDDIE: I can't tell you how
pleased I am
to see that Allegro.
FREDDIE: I can't tell you how
pleased I am
to see that Allegro.
FREDDIE: I can't tell you how
pleased I am
to see that Allegro.
Look at her. Look at her.
- PADDY: Hang on a minute.
- What?
What? That!
- Oh, the modifications.
- Yeah!
Last night, I took it down
the shop with the lads.
- What do you mean the lads?
- The Gurkhas.
Did a few things to it
to get it through.
We put bull bars on.
Did a few things to it
to get it through.
We put bull bars on.
Spare wheel. These are a must,
off-road tyres.
Roof rack, spotlights,
spare fuel, spare tyres,
you name it, Paddy,
this car has now got it.
This is just going to plough
through the jungle.
I get what you've done,
but, to be honest,
I think you've ruined it, pal.
He wants something untouched.
FREDDIE: But he wants one-offs.
He wants one-offs.
- This is now a one-off.
- You've muddied it up
too much,
- This is now a one-off.
- You've muddied it up
too much,
- he's not going to want that.
- Never mind
concentrating on my car,
- he's not going to want that.
- Never mind
concentrating on my car,
- he's not going to want that.
- Never mind
concentrating on my car,
how is that going to get
anywhere around here?
Look at it.
how is that going to get
anywhere around here?
Look at it.
PADDY: And, with that,
Fred decided to show
what the Allegro could do.
PADDY: And, with that,
Fred decided to show
what the Allegro could do.
PADDY: And, with that,
Fred decided to show
what the Allegro could do.
PADDY: And, with that,
Fred decided to show
what the Allegro could do.
Come on.
Come on, the Allegro.
(TYRES SKID)
Oh, it's not
going to be easy, this.
Are them the off-road tyres?
FREDDIE: Oh!
Yes!
(ENGINE REVS)
(BANGING)
Oh, the modifications
have paid off, Fred!
PADDY: Eventually, though,
with almost no help
from the Gurkhas...
PADDY: Eventually, though,
with almost no help
from the Gurkhas...
FREDDIE: Go, go.
PADDY: ... we started
to make tracks.
FREDDIE: Yes, go on!
- FREDDIE: We'll have to do
some clearing, lads.
- Yeah.
- FREDDIE: We'll have to do
some clearing, lads.
- Yeah.
That's it. Over here.
Ready? (GRUNTS)
Oh, I like this, teamwork.
I seen all that
when we got up, I thought,
"We've had it," but no.
I seen all that
when we got up, I thought,
"We've had it," but no.
- Not with these lads.
- PADDY:
All hands on log. That's it!
- Not with these lads.
- PADDY:
All hands on log. That's it!
- Not with these lads.
- PADDY:
All hands on log. That's it!
- We're on it.
- You have to move
your Bagheera.
- We're on it.
- You have to move
your Bagheera.
- Go move your Bagheera, Paddy.
- Bagheera?
It's yours in the way.
- Go move your Bagheera, Paddy.
- Bagheera?
It's yours in the way.
No, but I can't move it
for yours.
How's that?
- (BANG)
- PADDY: What are you doing?
- Sorry, Paddy.
- You've gone
into me pop-ups.
- Sorry, Paddy.
- You've gone
into me pop-ups.
- Sorry, Paddy.
- You've gone
into me pop-ups.
Why would you do that?
It's a one-off!
I can't get any spares for it!
FREDDIE: Clearing the tree,
we'd found our way
onto one of
the long-abandoned
logging tracks
onto one of
the long-abandoned
logging tracks
onto one of
the long-abandoned
logging tracks
that intersects the jungle.
A track that,
with a bit of luck,
might just lead to a road.
A track that,
with a bit of luck,
might just lead to a road.
A track that,
with a bit of luck,
might just lead to a road.
Come on. Yes.
Come on.
But luck wasn't on our side.
FREDDIE: Oh, my word.
Can't see the path.
Where are we going?
Oh!
- Oh, no, we're stopping again.
- Yeah.
PADDY:
Not more. Every two minutes
there's something.
PADDY:
Not more. Every two minutes
there's something.
- Not again.
- FREDDIE: Just gets thicker.
Come on.
Mate, we'll get through that,
just a bit of hacking.
- If we've got through that,
we can get through this.
- PADDY: Hang on a minute.
- If we've got through that,
we can get through this.
- PADDY: Hang on a minute.
Are you saying we're driving
through that?
Yeah, we're going to do
a bit of clearing,
move all this stuff out
the way and let's get through.
What? I've got my off-road tyres
jacked up, I'm fine.
Yeah, I haven't.
I'm two inches off the ground.
What was you saying before?
"Oh, the Bagheera.
"Even the name's designed
for the jungle."
Now you're backing out.
"Even the name's designed
for the jungle."
Now you're backing out.
"Even the name's designed
for the jungle."
Now you're backing out.
- Arjun?
- Yeah.
Is there not another way?
Can we not get off this road?
- Is there another way out?
- Paddy. Paddy.
We're in the jungle,
- Is there another way out?
- Paddy. Paddy.
We're in the jungle,
you're meant to get
through the jungle.
Excuse me, I'm having
a talk to me captain.
I'm going to get cracking.
Get your pickaxe out,
you'll love that.
- Where are we?
Where are we now?
- So, here.
- Where are we?
Where are we now?
- So, here.
- We're here.
- I think...
There's the one option,
the river.
- Didn't have you down there
for a chicken, Pad.
- River?
- Didn't have you down there
for a chicken, Pad.
- River?
- (FREDDIE CLUCKS)
- There's no road.
There's no road.
- (FREDDIE CLUCKS)
- There's no road.
There's no road.
If we can just get through
a little bit, we can get
to that river. That's not far.
If we can just get through
a little bit, we can get
to that river. That's not far.
If we can just get through
a little bit, we can get
to that river. That's not far.
- Paddy.
- What?
Have you had
the Gurkhas' motto?
What's that?
It's better to die
than be a coward.
- Look...
- (FREDDIE CLUCKING)
Chicken? We're still
getting there,
it's not about
being a chicken.
This is, this is...
Oh, this is... This is what
you're dealing with.
This is, this is...
Oh, this is... This is what
you're dealing with.
This is, this is...
Oh, this is... This is what
you're dealing with.
What we've got here
is a race, sunshine.
- Paddy.
- Ignore him.
- Paddy, take your Bagheera...
- Hang on a minute.
(HORN BLARES)
PADDY: So, Team Bagheera
had a new plan.
If we'd come in by river,
we could escape that way, too.
Captain Arjun had spotted
an old fishing settlement
nearby.
Captain Arjun had spotted
an old fishing settlement
nearby.
On foot, it was just
a short hack
through the jungle.
On foot, it was just
a short hack
through the jungle.
On foot, it was just
a short hack
through the jungle.
So, sending a scout on ahead
to look for anything
that could help us float,
we saddled up
and fired the Bagheera
back down the logging track.
FREDDIE: We're off. We're off.
Lads, let's pick up
the pace now,
we've got to beat Paddy.
Lads, let's pick up
the pace now,
we've got to beat Paddy.
- PADDY: Oh! Oh, oh, oh!
- Whoa!
MAN: Wahey! Oh!
Yes! It's like a rally car.
Yeah! The Bagheera
in its natural habitat.
MAN: It's impressive!
Oh, gets a bit rocky here.
Oh!
Oh! Oh! That's savage.
What the hell?
Oh! He'll still be
hacking his way
through the jungle.
Oh! He'll still be
hacking his way
through the jungle.
Oh! He'll still be
hacking his way
through the jungle.
For now, though,
I need my machete.
Words I'd never thought
I say, that.
"I need my machete."
Words I'd never thought
I say, that.
"I need my machete."
Words I'd never thought
I say, that.
"I need my machete."
Come on, lads, we've got
to beat Paddy now.
Whoa, whoa, whoa,
whoa, whoa!
Whoa!
It is doing the business
now, boys!
- I like this car!
- PADDY: Yeah!
We are on it now!
Whoa!
Wow! Oh!
But it's sideways, though.
Look at this!
FREDDIE: While Paddy McCrae
was on the charge,
I was doing whatever I could
to keep the Allegro moving.
Heave!
(GRUNTING)
Come on, we can do it!
- Argh! Heave!
- Push!
Yes! Yeah! Come on!
Right, stop it. Stop,
stop, stop, stop! Oh!
Feel like a Shire horse.
PADDY: A couple of miles east,
meanwhile, Team Bagheera
had reached the river.
PADDY: A couple of miles east,
meanwhile, Team Bagheera
had reached the river.
PADDY: A couple of miles east,
meanwhile, Team Bagheera
had reached the river.
Right.
- That's not the raft, is it?
- Oh, this is...
We can make better.
- That's not the raft, is it?
- Oh, this is...
We can make better.
- That's not the raft, is it?
- Oh, this is...
We can make better.
- That's not the raft, is it?
- Oh, this is...
We can make better.
We're going to have
to make it a lot better.
There's no middle to it.
We're going to have
to make it a lot better.
There's no middle to it.
I hate to say it, lads,
but we're in a rush here.
Push! Keep going! Keep going!
Yeah!
PADDY: Always bend
at the knees, Arjun.
Bend at the knees
not the back.
Down at the water,
the plan was simple,
bulk up the raft,
Down at the water,
the plan was simple,
bulk up the raft,
Down at the water,
the plan was simple,
bulk up the raft,
build a slipway...
- Have you got it?
- Try, Paddy?
Yeah.
and don't sink
the Bagheera.
Right. I'm going
to bring her down.
- Here we go.
- This side. Yep.
A little bit still.
Still. Still.
Okay!
Doesn't help
with the bloody rain.
Okay. Little bit. Yeah.
- Yeah?
- MAN: Yes. That's good.
Okay.
Come in, come in.
- Good.
- We're on, boys!
- We're on! We're on.
- Good.
He's left me.
Give him... Nothing.
FREDDIE: Oh, my word.
It's not the easiest path,
but it's the most rewarding.
Look at this. We're moving,
we're moving! We're only moving!
This car just amazes me.
And it might just have found
a way out.
Oh-ho-ho-ho!
Come on, we're back!
Come on, come on.
Get in, lads.
(THUNDER RUMBLING)
PADDY: Out on the raft,
meanwhile,
Operation River Rapids
was under way.
Although, to be fair,
not quite as rapidly
as we'd hoped.
Although, to be fair,
not quite as rapidly
as we'd hoped.
Although, to be fair,
not quite as rapidly
as we'd hoped.
So, to keep up morale,
I broke out the refreshments.
Time to get out
the big guns.
I've got the Angel Delight.
- MAN: Oh, thanks.
- PADDY: Have a cup.
On the top, there. On the top.
That's it.
Yeah, that's open.
Oh!
Strawberry.
It's the only flavour to have.
Little bit of milk.
Give it a stir. That's it.
Here we go. We're rallying now.
We're rallying.
- This is going pretty smooth.
- FREDDIE: Smooth.
It's the car, it's the car.
- This is going pretty smooth.
- FREDDIE: Smooth.
It's the car, it's the car.
- This is going pretty smooth.
- FREDDIE: Smooth.
It's the car, it's the car.
I'm glad you noticed.
Suspension.
Hydro gas.
It's an absolute dream.
FREDDIE: Oh, my word.
Oh!
Bloomin' heck!
- PADDY: It's a taste of home.
- MAN: Yeah.
Look at us. Four Gurkhas
eating Angel Delight.
Arjun, I've got to ask,
have you ever met Joanna Lumley?
FREDDIE: With the Bagheera
gradually floating out of
the running,
FREDDIE: With the Bagheera
gradually floating out of
the running,
Team Allegro was
out of the weather
and on the charge.
Team Allegro was
out of the weather
and on the charge.
Team Allegro was
out of the weather
and on the charge.
Oh, my word.
Is that... Is that...
It's not. Tarmac!
- Come on!
- (ALL CHEERING)
Whoa!
Whoa. Bit of land there, boys.
I think we can get in there.
- Paddling. Keep paddling, yeah.
- That's it, round we go.
Now, look at that
for a handbrake turn.
- Push.
- Whoa! Jesus!
Yeah.
Time is of the essence.
Out the way, boys.
I'm up, lads!
Come on, Bagheera! Yes! Yes,
Bagheera! Yeah!
We're on, boys!
PADDY: This was it.
The edge of the jungle.
We'd each found a road
and it would now be
a race 40 miles north-east
to the Brunei capital,
and it would now be
a race 40 miles north-east
to the Brunei capital,
Bandar Seri Begawan,
and the Sultan's palace.
But, while Flintoff had
escaped onto decent roads
and was making good time,
the river had spat me out
closer to the finish.
The Bagheera was well
back in the fight.
Come on!
Next stop, the Sultan
of Brunei's palace!
I have got to win this!
FREDDIE: Oh, it's singing.
69 horsepower.
And they're all
charging right now.
It's got to beat Paddy.
No way we can
be beaten by Paddy.
This is going to fly
to the palace.
I've got this covered!
Oh!
It's horrendous.
Oh, that is deep.
That is deep.
Urgh! Oh!
Not felt stress like it.
Oh, God.
When does this road
get any better?
- Which way?
- Turn left, please.
- Where?
- Left. Left.
- Hey, is...
- MAN: It's the highway now.
- Is this the motorway?
- Yeah.
Oh, here we come.
We're getting on the highway.
Now we're talking.
Look at us, this is the fastest
I've been in it so far.
MAN: Yeah.
But there's no way
that Paddy going through
the way he's gone
But there's no way
that Paddy going through
the way he's gone
can be going this fast.
Come on, the Allegro!
Tarmac. Yes, yes, yes, yes!
Let's go!
Now we're talking.
Let's open the taps. Come on!
We are motoring!
This road is fantastic!
And my odds were about
to improve even more.
(RATTLING)
Can you hear that rattle
from the engine now, can't you?
What's that?
Can you hear that rattle
from the engine now, can't you?
What's that?
Can you hear that rattle
from the engine now, can't you?
What's that?
It's starting to get hot.
Oh, there's a bit of smoke.
- Smoke?
- Yeah.
Are we getting smoke?
Oh, no. We're dying.
I'm losing power.
Oh, no, no, no, no.
- Smell that?
- Oh, yeah.
Geez!
What is wrong, Freddie?
Just getting hot, mate.
Just overheating.
- Just time, though, isn't it?
- Yeah.
And we've got no idea
where Paddy is.
What I'm looking for
is a really massive bridge.
The Gurkhas said,
once you're at that,
you know you're in Bandar.
The Gurkhas said,
once you're at that,
you know you're in Bandar.
The Gurkhas said,
once you're at that,
you know you're in Bandar.
Got to get to the Bandar Brid.
Do you know what? I reckon,
we've got the radiator here,
this is blocking it.
The number plate.
We flatten it,
might get more air in.
- Yeah.
- Do you reckon?
Push it down.
There's bits hanging off,
lost my rear view mirror,
- lost me air vents.
- (GEARS GRIND)
Oh, God, come on, gears.
Front bumper's fallen off.
I forgot about that.
Me Matra sign's fallen
off the back.
God, come on.
I haven't even seen
any signs yet.
That's it, crack on,
the Allegro.
The suspension
on the front left's gone.
The foot well down there,
where my feet are,
is boiling hot.
The foot well down there,
where my feet are,
is boiling hot.
The foot well down there,
where my feet are,
is boiling hot.
But it's still moving.
It's still chugging on.
I just don't know
for how much longer.
If I'm not mistaken...
This is a big bridge!
I'm in Bandar!
In the Bagheera!
Surely be,
we're getting closer now, look.
We're off the motorway,
we're going through the city,
- I can see the signs.
- Take a left, yeah.
Bandar Seri Begawan.
We're getting closer.
Come on!
(GEARS LURCH)
No, no, no, no,
no, no, no. Not now.
Not now, not here.
Oh, God.
The lights have turned red.
(GEARS SCREECH)
- (HORNS HONK)
- Sorry! Coming over.
Oh! Is that it?
Yes, thank you.
Oh, God,
has it jumped out again?
(HORNS HONK)
Going to have to try
a hard start in second.
Sorry!
Going to have to try
a hard start in second.
Sorry!
Going to have to try
a hard start in second.
Sorry!
Going to have to try
a hard start in second.
Sorry!
Oh! (GRUNTS)
(FREDDIE GROANS)
Just find one, big, last push.
Please, please, please.
Where is it?
I mean, it's a palace,
how can I miss a palace?
How close? How close?
- Somewhere around here.
- What, we're close
to the palace?
- Somewhere around here.
- What, we're close
to the palace?
PADDY: Come on!
Let's do it
for the Gurkhas, Bagheera.
Come on!
There's traffic around now.
Come on, move!
- (GEARS SCREECH)
- PADDY: Whoa!
That's not sounding good.
- (GEARS SCREECH)
- PADDY: Whoa!
That's not sounding good.
- (GEARS SCREECH)
- PADDY: Whoa!
That's not sounding good.
Do I change to fourth?
Do I risk it?
Oh, I risked it!
He's done it!
Come on. Come on, Palace.
Left. Left.
Oh, you are kidding me.
You are absolutely kidding me.
(LAUGHS)
All right, Paddy? Hey?
Yous no way
you've gone through
the jungle. No way.
Yous no way
you've gone through
the jungle. No way.
Yous no way
you've gone through
the jungle. No way.
Ask the lads,
ask the Gurkhas.
How's that got here
before that?
Oh. Oh.
See, soon as you get here
with that, this happens.
- Is he in?
- We've, erm...
I've bought it
for the Sultan.
GUARD: No, no, no,
don't bring it here.
- Shall I leave
the keys with you?
- No, no, no, no.
- Shall I leave
the keys with you?
- No, no, no, no.
- Shall I leave them
in the ignition?
- You can't park there.
- Shall I leave them
in the ignition?
- You can't park there.
I'll leave them in here.
- Park over there.
- He's saying go.
Get in the car.
- Unbelievable, boys.
- Thank you so much.
Thank you.
- Unbelievable, boys.
- Thank you so much.
Thank you.
- Had a good time
with you. Thank you.
- PADDY: Boys.
- Had a good time
with you. Thank you.
- PADDY: Boys.
It's been a pleasure.
Been a pleasure, lads.
- (CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
- CHRIS: Well done. Well done.
Impressive cars, them.
Impressive.
I am absolutely staggered
they survived.
What we've learned is,
if you want to cross a jungle,
you don't need a 4x4,
what you need is
a knackered old car
you don't need a 4x4,
what you need is
a knackered old car
and a highly trained
team of Gurkhas?
They were good lads.
They were great lads,
weren't they?
- Unbelievable.
- Very good lads.
But the cars, I mean,
the Bagheera,
- how on Earth did it survive?
- It was amazing!
Everything that we've
thrown at that car,
it just carried on going.
Everything that we've
thrown at that car,
it just carried on going.
And the Allegro, you know,
the most unreliable car
in history,
And the Allegro, you know,
the most unreliable car
in history,
you found the only reliable one
ever made.
I got to like it more and more
as the journey went on.
That was British Leyland
at its finest.
Well, Chris, now it's down to
you to choose which is
the best of our rare cars.
Well, Chris, now it's down to
you to choose which is
the best of our rare cars.
Well, Chris, now it's down to
you to choose which is
the best of our rare cars.
Well, Chris, now it's down to
you to choose which is
the best of our rare cars.
- It's like choosing between two
really ugly children.
- (LAUGHTER)
- It's like choosing between two
really ugly children.
- (LAUGHTER)
- It's like choosing between two
really ugly children.
- (LAUGHTER)
- Ooh!
- Erm... I can't... Look,
- I have to give it...
- Yeah.
to the Allegro.
- What?
- Yes!
I didn't see that coming!
Get in! Get in, Paddy!
Oh! Yes! The Allegro!
- It's all right, Paddy.
- He had off-road tyres on it!
You did well.
Okay, look, you're double denim
and you're angry.
- Shocked.
- You're angry.
But the fact is the Allegro's
an object of hate
and it succeeded
at something in its life.
I've got to say, I fell in love
with the Allegro myself.
Me too and the Bagheera
just kept going.
You never thought it would get
through that terrain,
- how low it was
at the start.
- Yep. Both did well.
- how low it was
at the start.
- Yep. Both did well.
(LAUGHTER)
I presume you've left them
in the jungle, right?
No, we were never
going to leave them
for the Sultan, were we?
No, we were never
going to leave them
for the Sultan, were we?
No. Not a chance.
So, instead, we shipped
our rare car heroes
back home
So, instead, we shipped
our rare car heroes
back home
So, instead, we shipped
our rare car heroes
back home
and we've given them
a lick of paint
just to freshen them up.
and we've given them
a lick of paint
just to freshen them up.
- Bring them in, lads.
- In they come. In they come.
I love this car.
Come on!
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
Yeah!
I love this car.
Beautiful.
That's all for tonight.
We'll see you next week.
Thanks for watching. Goodnight.
(CHEERING AND APPLAUSE)
(THEME MUSIC PLAYING)